#### Contact

22825 ARCADIA ST

5868012860 (Home) bobbidigi34@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/robertallendev (LinkedIn) robertjallen.dev/ (Portfolio)

# Top Skills

React.js

Agile Methodologies

Web Development

# Languages

**Python** 

English

**JavaScript** 

## Certifications

Certificate of Completion: JavaScript

Course

**PHP** 

Certificate of Completion: HTML

**Fundamentals** 

Front-End Web Developer

Nanodegree

#### Honors-Awards

Most Likely To Become a StartUp

# Robert Allen

Team Lead at Lambdaschool | Full Stack Dev | HTML & CSS | JavaScript | React & Redux | NodeJS | SQL | Python

Detroit Metropolitan Area

# Summary

I've always been either coding or tinkering with something. Gravitating towards development felt very natural. Over the years I have worked in a few different languages. My most recent passion is building web apps with React and Redux, using the foursquare and google maps API's. I am also quite fond of NextJS. Let me know if you have any fun projects going on.

If you are reaching out about an opportunity it would be great if you would email me at bobbidigi34@gmail.com. Thanks!

# Experience

Self-Employed Software Engineer January 2019 - Present (2 years 4 months)

Greater Detroit Area

Lambda School Team Lead November 2019 - February 2020 (4 months) remote

- Lead a team of students, providing daily feedback and code reviews
- Mentor students in areas of effective learning, programming and provide additional challenges to advance their learning
- Provide reliable resources in areas of communications, programming and personal well-being for students
- Make sure students are progressing in their curriculum by reviewing code, providing feedback and one-on-one code debugging with students
- Facilitate daily stand-up meetings to build teamwork, idea sharing and check progress and understanding

# Udacity

Independent Consultant

February 2019 - November 2019 (10 months)

Mountain View, California

Description: As a consultant to educational platform(s), such as Udacity, I utilize my specialized knowledge in the field(s) of programming and web development, and my strong communication skills to provide project reviews and other student support services.

# Education

#### Lambda School

full stack web development · (2019 - 2020)

### Udacity

Front-end web development, Front-end web development · (2018 - 2018)

#### Free Code Camp

Full Stack Web Development Certification, Computer Software Engineering (2016 - 2017)

#### Harvard University

cs50, Computer Science · (2016 - 2017)

## Macomb Community College

IT Pro cert, Information Technology · (2000 - 2010)